Finding Aid for William Brownrigg papers, 1919-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William Brownrigg papers 1919-1967
Brownrigg, William, 1893-1969.
4 linear feet
85957 Aa 2
First director of the Michigan Civil Service Commission and director of personnel at U.S. Department of Justice under Attorney General Frank Murphy. Correspondence, speeches, and book reviews concerning his public career and his work for the governor; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of William Brownrigg (donor no. 4760 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
William Brownrigg was a native of Manistee, Michigan. Following graduation from the University of Michigan, Brownrigg devoted his career to civil service reform, serving at one time as the executive officer of the California State Personnel Board before being selected as Michigan's personnel director in the gubernatorial administration of Frank Murphy in the mid-1930s. When Murphy came to Washington DC as Attorney General, Brownrigg was selected to head the justice department's new Division of Personnel Supervision and Management.
The collection was arranged into the following series: Correspondence, Speeches; Other papers: reports, memoranda, drafts, etc.; and Miscellaneous. Correspondents in the collection include Prentiss M. Brown, Stuart Chase, V. O. Key, Edward H. Litchfield, George Meader, Frank Murphy, and James K. Pollock.
Subjects:
Brownrigg, William, 1893-1969.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Public administration.; United States. Dept. of Justice.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Brownrigg, William, 1893-1969.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Contributors:
Brown, Prentiss Marsh, 1889-1973.; Chase, Stuart, 1888-1985.; Key, V. O. (Valdimer Orlando), 1908-1963.; Litchfield, Edward H. (Edward Harold), 1914-1968.; Meader, George, 1907-; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1936-1956, 25 folders (Box 1)
  - 1957-1967, 18 folders (Box 2)
- Speeches
  - Undated and 1934-1939, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Other papers: reports, memoranda, drafts, etc.
  - Undated and 1919-February 1940, 20 folders (Box 3)
  - March 1940-1961, 19 folders (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Reviews of The Human Enterprise Process (written by Brownrigg) (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Brown, Prentiss Marsh, 1889-1973
Feb. 28, 1940, March 19, 1940
Chase, Stuart, 1888-1985.
Feb. 23, 1961
Key, V.O. (Valdimer Orlando), 1908-1963.
Nov. 5, 1956
Litchfield, Edward H. (Edward Harold), 1914-1968
Sept. 4, 1940, 1941-1942, 1952
Meader, George, 1907-
Jan. 20, 1958
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Dec. 29, 1938, 1939-1940, Jan. 24, 1941, Jan. 27, 1941
Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-
1936, Feb. 15, 1939, 1940-1943, 1952, Jan. 26, 1953, Oct. 22, 1954, Dec. 24, 1958, Dec. 29, 1958